Finding Aid for the Kay Sugahara Papers LSC.2354
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kay Sugahara papers
1915-2014
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.2354
86.8 Linear Feet (172 boxes, 23 flat boxes, 8 oversize flat boxes, and 5 shoe boxes)
Kay Sugahara, a millionaire by the age of 29, was sometimes referred to as the "Nisei Onassis" by other second generation Japanese Americans. He was imprisoned in two West Coast camps after the attack on Pearl Harbor, yet managed to free himself through his recruitment into the Office of Strategic Services (OSS), the forerunner to the Central Intelligence Agency. After working for the OSS during the war, Sugahara fought to improve relations between the U.S. and Japan, build Asian American communities on a local and national scale, and as Fairfield-Maxwell Ltd. Chairman, he became a millionaire once again by making tankers in Japan for U.S. oil companies. The collection contains Sugahara's business, trip, and personal files.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audio and audiovisual materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed audio and audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Fairfied-Maxwell, Ltd. by Anthony J. Dowd; Gift; 2017.
Custodial History
The date span of materials within this collection extends before the birth of Kay Sugahara and beyond his death date because his colleagues at Fairfield-Maxwell, Ltd. and his family members added items.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID:9985427553606533
Biographical / Historical
Kay Sugahara, born in Seattle, Washington on March 18, 1909, was sometimes referred to as the "Nisei Onassis" by other second generation Japanese Americans. His father Kei Sugahara, the 10th son of a Sendai Samurai was born in Japan and immigrated to the U.S. between 1900 and 1905. His mother Taki Sugahara was born Shimane Ken. His family moved to Los Angeles between 1912 and 1913, where Kay attended public schools. Both parents died by the time he was 13.
After Sugahara graduated from the University of California, Los Angeles in 1932 with a degree in economics and political science, he opened his own firm, Universal Foreign Service Company, and served as president or director of most of the Japanese American organizations in Los Angeles. While president of the Japanese American Citizens League, Los Angeles Chapter, the membership created and promoted the Nisei Festival which revitalized the Little Tokyo neighborhood. After much resistance, he became the first Japanese American customs broker in mainland U.S.A., and at 29 he became a millionaire.
After the Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor, Sugahara and his family were forcibly removed from the West Coast along with all persons of Japanese ancestry. They were held for a time in horse stables at the Santa Anita Racetrack and then sent to Granada (Camp Amache) in Colorado. In 1942 Sugahara joined the Office of Strategic Services (OSS), which would later become the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA). Sugahara reported to experts on Japan, the Honorable Joseph Grew and Eugene Dooman to help shape post-War Japanese policies. He was influenced by Commanding Officer, General William Donovan, to focus his energies on strategic decisions in business.
After the war, Sugahara organized the American Council for Japan at the request of the U.S. State Department, in order to reorient U.S. opinion towards Japan and reduce public hostility so trade relations could develop. His office was used as the main headquarters where his personnel worked. American Council for Japan members talked with every U.S. mission going to Japan to influence a shift from punitive peace terms to a viable situation so Japan could grow economically.
During the Korean War, Sugahara headed a confidential U.S. procurement mission to Japan to purchase strategic materials during the Korean War. He also arranged barter in 1956 between the U.S. Department of Agriculture and Japanese titanium producers for $30 million each way. This arrangement was supported by Senator William Knowland of California, Senate Minority Leader, and the White House.
In 1957 he worked with Mobil Oil and changed the closed market system of the Seven Sisters on oil so that domestic Japanese refineries could receive "equal access." Finally, Sugahara served as Chairman of the Board of Fairfield-Maxwell Ltd. (FML), a company founded on May 23, 1957, to broker sales between Mobil Oil and Japanese-owned refineries. FML soon expanded into other maritime-related activities such as the building, sale and leasing of tankers and general cargo shipping, beginning with the launch of the Marion in 1960. Between 1969 and 1972 he worked to break the secret prohibition against chartering Asian tankers. Between 1977 and 1978 as Chairman of American Mercantile Company, he financed a campaign for "open access" for U.S. agricultural products to Japan markets. In 1978, FML launched Great American Lines to operate the Sunbelt Dixie, a first-of-its-kind refrigerated car-carrier that brought Toyota automobiles to the U.S. and was able to return to Japan with Florida grapefruit.
In 1981 Sugahara was asked to become chairman of the U.S. Asian Institute and articulate the political and economic aspirations of five million U.S. Asians. On September 25, 1988, Kay Sugahara passed away at his home in the New York suburb of Pelham Manor, at the age of 79. He was survived by his wife Yone and his sons, Kaytaro, Bryan and Byron. In 2002, Yone passed away and is now interred with Kay at Arlington National Cemetery.
This note was created from Kay Sugahara's 1988 September 23 Curriculum Vitae and his 1982 March 28 Profile on Kay Sugahara.
Scope and Contents
This collection spans 1915 to 2014 and contains Kay Sugahara's business, trip, and personal files. The business files document his activities at Fairfield-Maxwell Ltd. (FML), the Dooman Group, the Office of Strategic Services (OSS), the American Council on Japan, the American Mercantile Company (AMC), the US-Asia Institute (USIA), and associated activities. The trip files document his travels related to FML, USIA, conferences, speeches, ceremonies, christenings, White House inaugurations, and vacation activities. The personal files include scrapbooks, photo albums, correspondence, diaries, appointment books, documentation of Granada, Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) reports, biographical manuscripts, awards, audio, audiovisual, and press materials.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Business files, 1954-2007
Series 2: Trip files, 1972-1988
Series 3: Personal files, 1915-2014
Related Materials
Japanese American Research Project (Yuji Ichioka) collection of material about Japanese in the United States (Collection 2010). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Japanese Americans -- United States -- History; Japanese Americans -- Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945; Entrepreneurship -- United States; Japan -- Foreign economic relations -- United States; United States -- Foreign economic relations -- Japan
- Series 1: Business files, 1950-1988
  Scope and Contents
  The business files document Sugahara's activities at Fairfield-Maxwell Ltd. (FML), the Dooman Group, the Office of Strategic Services (OSS), the American Council on Japan, the American Mercantile Company (AMC), the US-Asia Institute (USIA), and associated activities.
  - KS - expense reports and itineraries, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - KS - expense reports and itineraries, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - KS - expense reports and itineraries, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - KS - expense reports and itineraries, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sunbelt Dixie, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - FII brochures and photos, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Burmah Oil, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Somalia, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ships - photos and reports, 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - PSK - Komatsu correspondence, 1962 December-1963 December (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - PSK - Komatsu correspondence, 1961 March-1962 September (Box 10, Folder 1-7)
  - PSK - Komatsu correspondence, 1958 March-June, 1958 September, 1959 February-1959 December, 1960 March, 1960 August, 1960 December-1961 March (Box 11, Folder 1-8)
  - PSK - Komatsu correspondence, 1954 December-1955 December, 1955 October-1956 February, 1956 June-1957 January, 1956 November-1957 December 1958 March, 1960 August-1960 December (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
  - Chronological file, 1976 June 1-1976 July 12 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Chronological files, 1975 September 5-1976 May 30, 1976 July 13-1976 August 11 (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
  - Chronological files, 1974 October 18-1975 September 4 (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
  - Chronological files, 1974 January 1-1974 October 10 (Box 15, Folder 1-6)
  - Chronological files, 1978 February 21-1978 December 31 (Box 16, Folder 1-6)
  - Chronological files, 1977 August 3-1978 February 17, 1978 May 9-1978 July 18 (Box 17, Folder 1-6)
  - Chronological files, 1977 January 3-1977 February 14, 1977 March 15-1977 August 2 (Box 18, Folder 1-6)
  - Chronological files, 1976 August 11-1976 December 30, 1977 February 15-1977 March 14, 1979 January 2-1979 March 16 (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
  - Chronological files, 1979 March 19-1979 August 10, 1979 September 17-1979 October 19 (Box 20, Folder 1-6)
  - Chronological files, 1979 August 13-1979 September 14, 1979 October 22-1979 December 31 (Box 21, Folder 1-4)
  - Salih Al-As'Ad - PAC, 1973-1976 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Aquatronics, 1974-1975 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Atwood, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Bank of Tokyo Trust, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Bishop, Max, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Caltex, 1973-1975 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Clearview Fishery, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Colish, Harry, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Conoco, 1973-1975 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Corcoran - International Golf Assn., 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Crude Oil Information, 1973-1975 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Saudi Al'Sowayel/Saudi Arabia, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Arizona Iron Ore, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Shaheen, 1973-1975 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - American Mercantile Company, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - TFL/Lane/Morocco/Iran, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Bishop, Max, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Tanker Stockpile, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Tanker Market, 1973-1975 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Taiyo Gyogyo, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Sumitamo Trust, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Carter Energy Proposal, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Carter/Kirbo, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Sumitomo Shoji-Shibayama, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Diplomatic Washington, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Citrus - Seald-Sweet, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Chapman, Paul, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Fairfield Maxwell Financial Statements, 1973, 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Fairfield Maxwell Reorganization Study, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Fairfield Maxwell Results of Operations, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Diplomatic Japan, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Fairfield-Maxwell, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Clearview Leasing, 1975-1977 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Georgia Port Authority, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Fairfield-Maxwell Services - Downard, 1975-1978 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Fairfield Maxwell Financial Reports, 1974-1977 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - IHI, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Indonesia/Simon, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Great American Lines - end, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Saudi Tanker Owners Group, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Skaarup Shipping - Host, 1973-1975 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Skory, David, 1973-1975 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Japan Line, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Jerome Joseph, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Koyo, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Kurio - Hawaii/Saudi Arabia, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - MMS/MIS, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 4-3)
  - LNG's, 1975-1977 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Mobil Oil, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Kuwait, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Mussallam, Ali, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Nakabe, Tojiro, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Nakao/Toho Pictures, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Natomas, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Nigeria, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - New York Navigation, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - O'Connell, Edmund, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Odyssey, 1975-1977 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - OSS, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Phillips, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Philippines - Subic Bay, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Preference Flag, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - REL, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Samarco, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Shaheen, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Sharjah, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Smith, Leland, 1975-1977 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Shimanouchi - Keidanren, 1972-1977 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Sunbelt Dixie Ceremony, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Tanker Market, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Tanker Regulations/Oil Pollution, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Texaco/Japan Line, 1976-1977 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - TSP/Japan Line, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Transshipment/Cayman, 1976-1977 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - 200 Mile Fishing Zone, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Y-S Line, 1974-1977 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Ashland Oil, 1976-1977 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Bishop, Max, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Campo Tankers, 1973-1978 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Chapman, Paul, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Citrus, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Crude Oil, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Conoco, 1976-1978 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Daitoh Trading/Yano, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Diplomatic -Washington, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Directors Meetings, 1976-1978 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Fairfield Industries, 1977-1978 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Financial Statements - FML & Subs, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - FML Cash Position, 1973-1975 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Fairfield-Maxwell, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Golf, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Grumman, 1976-1979 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Insurance/Wills, 1976-1978 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Land Investments, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Hellen Shipping/LFR's/Lighterage Express, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Matsunaga, 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - MMS/MIS/MDN, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - PSK - 1461 correspondence, 1970 January-1970 December (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - TKO 69 KS letters, 1969 August-1969 September (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - KS Letters from Japan, 1970 March-1970 May (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - PSK 1188-1460, 1967 April 1-1969 December 29 (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
  - PSK 1070-1187, 1966 January-1967 March 31 (Box 34, Folder 1-3)
  - Index file for letters - PSK, PTD, YNM, TO, 1966-1970 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Komatsu, Mark, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Kousi, John, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - LNG, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Lux Ore - Tetelo, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Matsunaga, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 4-6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 7-8)
  - Mobil, 1971-1973 (Box 35, Folder 10-11)
  - K. Nakabe, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Nakabe, Tojiro, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Olympic International, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Ohliger, Floyd, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - OOC - Paul Abt, Neville Conyers, Howard Auld, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
  - Petromin, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - REL, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Reinhard, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Saudia Arabia, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 8-10)
  - Saudia Arabia - Ohliger, 1973 July (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Taiyo Gyogyo KK, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Taiyo Gyogyo, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - TFL Taiyo - Lane, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Taiyo Shoshen, 1970-1973 (Box 37, Folder 5-6)
  - Tanker file SSK 228 CON 1009 ELF, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Zen-Noh, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - San Francisco trip correspondence, 1973 September (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - SSK - Mobil, 1972 July (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - SASEBO - SSK - new building, 1970-1972 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Smith, Leland A., 1972 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Stringfellow - Internet, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Staff meetings, 1972-1973 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Sumitomo Shoji, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Misc. film production - FM investment, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Mobil Commission, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Mohammed Bin Salih Bin Sultan, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - NIOC Virginia Shipping, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Occidental - Hammer, 1973-1974 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Odyssey, 1970-1974 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Okinawa Dockyard, 1973 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Oliver, George, 1972-1973 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Petromin, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Post Corp Hawaii, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Rolftite, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Saudi information, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Japan trip correspondence, 1975 January (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Samarco Reception, 1975 January (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Sanko/Stanley, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Sasebo Heavy Industries, 1973-1974 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Saudi Arabia Crude Applications, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Olympic International - Azuma, 1972-1974 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - SASCO/SAMCO Saudi Arabia Shipping Company, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Sowayel - Saudi Arabia, 1973-1974 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Seibu Sekiyu - Matsuda, 1972-1974 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Shaheen Qeii Trip, 1975 April (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Shell, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Smith/Kline, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Leland, 1973-1974 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Sumitomo Shipbuilding and Machinery Co., 1973-1974 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Taiyo Gyogyo, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Taiyo Shoshen, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Texaco, 1973 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Morocco - TFL Lane, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Tudela - Venezuela, 1972-1974 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Vasquez, George, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Virgin Islands Refinery Corp., 1973 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Wareing - Psi/Cyclo/Ball, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Zennoh, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 7-9)
  - NYG correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 1-5)
  - NYG correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 42, Folder 1-6)
  - NYG correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 43, Folder 1-6)
  - YNM Daitoh correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 44, Folder 1-8)
  - YNM Daitoh correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 45, Folder 1-9)
  - YNM Daitoh correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 46, Folder 1-9)
  - King Resources, 1970 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - IRL Stringfellow memos, 1970 (Box 47, Folder 1-5)
  - Refineries, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - SAJOC - Saudi Arabia Japan Oil Company, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - US Japan Foods, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Tojiro Nakabe, 1978-1979 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Ohliger, Floyd, 1974-1979 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - REL, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Rizzo - Energy, 1979-1980 (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
  - Seald-Sweet, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Shimanouchi, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Sunbelt Dixie Ceremonies, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Taiyo Gyogyo, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 2-3)
  - Tanker Market, 1978-1979 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Sun World Pure Gold, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Tanker Safety Regs, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Toyota Motor Sales, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - US Japan Foods, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - FMK Chronological file, 1978 January-December (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Agro Chemical International, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Alpine Shipping/Kulik, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - American Mercantile, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 6-7)
  - Caravel Tankers, 1973-1977 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Chapman, Duff and Paul, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Citrus, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Dr. H Colish, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Comtek Resources-Price, 1979-1980 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Conoco, 1979-1980 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Daitoh Trading, 1979-1980 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Daty - Clay Slurry, 1978-1980 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Democratic National Committee, Asia-Pacific Am., 1980 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Chapman, Duff and Paul, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Bishop, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Business cards, undated (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Citrus, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - White House, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Fujibeton files, circa 1970s (Box 52, Folder 3-17)
  - Fujibeton LBD, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - Kousi, John, 1974-1977 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Levine/Sasetru, 1979-1980 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Mexico - Fishing, 1980-1981 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - American Express - James R. Greene, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - American Bureau of Shipping, 1977-1980 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - AMC Weekly Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 53, Folder 9-10)
  - AMC Board Minutes, 1982-1984 (Box 54, Folder 1-6)
  - Bermuda, 1982-1983 (Box 54, Folder 7-8)
  - Bank of Tokyo - Tokyo Office, 1982 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Bishop, 1980-1982 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - International Barter, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Chapman, Duff and Paul, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Mark Buchman, Union Bank, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - William J. Casey, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - President Carter, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Computer, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Conoco - Nicandros, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - FML files, 1982-1983 (Box 55, Folder 8-20)
  - FMSL, Peter Bingham, 1982 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Far East - America Council, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Consul Gen. Takeo Iguchi, 1982 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Japan Line, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Kurio, 1981-1982 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Japan Society, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Norman Lau Kee - Battery City Development, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Komatsu Seisakijo, 1981-1982 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Kyoto Seida Godo - Mr. Uchida, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Lovejoy, Wasson, 1973-1981 (Box 56, Folder 10-11)
  - Mario Machado, 1982 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Maritime Data Network, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Yasuko Masaki, 1982 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Seibu Oil Co., Inc., 1982 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Shipping, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - NYG Chronological files, 1980 January-1981 June (Box 57, Folder 1-5)
  - NYG Chronological files, 1980 June-1981 February (Box 58, Folder 1-4)
  - NYG Chronological files, 1981 February-1981 August (Box 59, Folder 1-4)
  - NYG Chronological files, 1981 September-1982 March (Box 60, Folder 1-3)
  - NYG Chronological files, 1982 March-1982 September (Box 61, Folder 1-3)
  - NYG Chronological files, 1982 September-1983 March (Box 62, Folder 1-3)
  - NYG Chronological files, 1983 April-1983 June (Box 63, Folder 1-2)
  - Seiba Sekiya, 1981 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Semerad International Inc., 1981 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Malcolm Skall, 1981 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Stockton Road, 1980-1981 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Sudan, 1981 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Showa Oil, 1980-1981 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Diplomatic Washington, 1981 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Sumitomo, 1981 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Taiyo Shoshen, 1982 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Tudela, 1979 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - YS Line, 1979-1980 (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Japanese American Cultural Community Center, 1981 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Craig Spence dinner, 1981 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - China material, 1979-1981 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - REL Board Minutes, 1980 December (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Nigeria notes and clippings, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 1-3)
  - Mexico workshop materials, 1979-1980 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Saud Al-Sowayel, 1981-1982 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Nigerian Rice Project files, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 6-8)